menupages.ie 2015-12-18

# Privacy and Security

**Here at MenuPages we care about your privacy and respect your privacy rights.**

###  What Personal Information About Customers Does MenuPages.ie Gather?

The information we learn from customers helps us personalise and continually improve your shopping experience at MenuPages.ie. We use the information to handle orders, deliver products and services, process payments, communicate with you about orders, products, services and promotional offers, update our records and generally maintain your accounts with us, display content such as wish lists and customer reviews and recommend merchandise and services that might be of interest to you. We also use this information to improve our store and platform, prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our website and enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf.

###  Here are the types of information we gather.

Information You Give Us: we receive and store any information you enter on our website or give us in any other way. Click here to see examples of what we collect. You can choose not to provide certain information but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of our features. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests, customising future shopping for you, improving our stores, and communicating with you. Automatic Information: we receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many websites, we use "cookies" and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses MenuPages.ie. Click here to see examples of the information we receive. A number of companies offer utilities designed to help you visit websites anonymously. Although we will not be able to provide you with a personalised experience at MenuPages.ie if we cannot recognise you, we want you to be aware that these tools exist. E-mail Communications: to help us make e-mails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open e-mail from MenuPages.ie if your computer supports such capabilities. We also compare our customer list to lists received from other companies in an effort to avoid sending unnecessary messages to our customers. If you do not want to receive e-mail or other mail from us, please adjust your Customer Communication Preferences. Information from Other Sources: we might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information. Click here to see examples of the information we receive.

###  What About Cookies?

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognise your browser and to provide features such as 1-Click purchasing, New for You, personalised greetings and storage of items in your Shopping Basket between visits. The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. However, cookies allow you to take full advantage of some of MenuPages.ie's most innovative and useful features and we recommend that you leave them turned on. If you do leave cookies turned on, be sure to sign off when you finish using a shared computer. Click here for more information on how to sign off. Do MenuPages.ie and MenuPages Jersey Share the Information They Receive?

Information about our customers is an important part of our business and we are not in the business of selling it to others. MenuPages.ie share customer information only as described below and that are either subject to this Privacy Notice.

###  How Secure Is Information About Me?

We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. We reveal only the last five digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. Of course, we transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of personally identifiable customer information. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you. It is important for you to protect against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when you finish using a shared computer. Click here for more information on how to sign off. What About Third-Party Advertisers and Links to Other Websites?

Our site may include third-party advertising and links to other websites. We do not provide any personally identifiable customer information to these advertisers or third-party websites. Click here for some examples as well as information on how to contact these companies to learn more or opt-out of their information collection practices.

These third-party websites and advertisers, or Internet advertising companies working on their behalf, sometimes use technology to send (or "serve") the advertisements that appear on our website directly to your browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (also known as action tags or single-pixel gifs), and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalise advertising content. We do not have access to or control over cookies or other features that they may use, and the information practices of these advertisers and third-party websites are not covered by this Privacy Notice. Please contact them directly for more information about their privacy practices. In addition, the Network Advertising Initiative offers useful information about Internet advertising companies (also called "ad networks" or "network advertisers"), including information about how to opt-out of their information collection.

###  Surveys & Competitions

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or competitions. Participation in these surveys or competitions is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and delivery address), and demographic information (such as address, age and income level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. No personal information will be retained for longer than is necessary or used for any undisclosed purpose.

###  What Information Can I Access?

MenuPages.ie gives you access to a broad range of information about your account and your interactions with MenuPages.ie and MenuPages Jersey for the limited purpose of viewing and, in certain cases, updating that information. Click here to see some examples. This list will change as our website evolves.

###  What Choices Do I Have?

As discussed above, you can always choose not to provide information, even though it might be needed to make a purchase or to take advantage of such MenuPages.ie features as your About You area, Wish Lists and Customer Reviews. You can add or update certain information on pages such as those listed in Which Information Can I Access?. When you update information, we usually keep a copy of the previous version for our records. If you do not want to receive e-mail or other mail from us, please adjust your Customer Communication Preferences. (If you do not want to receive Conditions of Use and other legal notices from us, such as this Privacy Notice, those notices will still govern your use of MenuPages.ie and orders placed with MenuPages.ie and MenuPages Jersey, and it is your responsibility to review them for changes.) The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. However, you will not be able to use such important features as 1-Click and New for You if you do not use cookies. Are Children Allowed to Use MenuPages.ie?

MenuPages.ie does not sell products for purchase by children. We sell children's products for purchase by adults. If you are under 18, you may use MenuPages.ie only with the involvement of a parent or guardian.

###  The types of personal information we collect and how we collect it:

**Information you provide upon registration:** in order to make use of certain services provided through the website such as the forums and email newsletters you will provide us with information about yourself and you will be able to select how we use your information for marketing purposes; We will only use your information in accordance with your instructions and as set out in this privacy policy.

**Demographic and other data:** this website uses cookies, web analytics and web logs to collect information about your use of our site, information about your computer such as your computer’s IP address and browser type, demographic data and, if you arrived at our site via a link from a third party site, the URL of the linking page. If you have registered an account with us, it may also collect your name and email address.

**Email communications:** we use web beacons in our emails to track the success of our marketing campaigns. If you open an email from us, we can see which of the pages of our website you visited. Our web beacons don’t store any information on your computer but, by communicating with our cookies on your computer, they can tell us when you have opened an email from us. We may keep track of the emails that we send you. We also keep a record of what communications you have selected to receive or not to receive. If you would like to opt out of receiving such emails, please click the “unsubscribe” link in the email and follow the instructions.

###  Who we may share your personal information with:

**Agents:** we use third parties to perform certain functions on our behalf including fulfilling orders, sending emails, organising and managing competitions, promotions, surveys or polls, removing repetitive information from customer lists, comment hosting, website analysis, data analysis, translation services and processing credit card payments. They will have access to your personal information if necessary to perform their function but they cannot use it or disclose it for any other purpose, unless you have specifically given them consent to do so. 

**Aggregate Information:** we may share aggregate, non-personally identifiable information, such as demographics and website usage statistics, with advertisers, sponsors and other organisations.

**Third-Party Ad Serving and Audience and Traffic Measurement Services:** we may use a third-party network advertiser to serve the advertisements on this website or we may use an audience or traffic measurement service to analyse the traffic on this website. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to this website and other websites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products or websites you might be interested in. Audience and traffic measurement services allow us to collect anonymous traffic and behavioural information from the website by monitoring anonymous visitor activity. This website’s advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer if you choose to have your cookies enabled in your browser.

###  Cookie Opt-Outs

Some people find the idea of a website storing information on their device a little intrusive, in particular when the information is stored and used by a third party. For example, you may object to being served advertising which is targeted to your interests based on your browsing history. If you would prefer to opt out of cookies, it is possible to control cookies by following the steps below, however you should be aware that you might lose some features and functionality of the website if you do so

Cookies, including those which have already been set, can be deleted from your hard drive. You can also change the preferences/settings in your web browser to control cookies. In some cases, you can choose to accept cookies from the primary site, but block them from third parties. In others, you can block cookies from specific advertisers, or clear out all cookies. Deleting or blocking cookies may reduce functionality of the site. To learn more about how to reject cookies, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or go to the help menu within your internet browser.

**Opting out of Behavioural Advertising Cookies:**

If you would like to disable “third party” cookies generated by advertisers or providers of targeted advertising services, you can turn them off by going to the third party’s website and getting them to generate a one-time “no thanks” cookie that will stop any further cookies being written to your machine.

You can find out how to decline online behavioural advertising by visiting:

###  Conditions of Use, Notices, and Revisions

If you choose to visit MenuPages.ie, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Notice and our Conditions of Use, including limitations on damages and application of the laws of Ireland. If you have any concern about privacy at MenuPages.ie, please e-mail us a thorough description and we will try to resolve the issue for you.

Our business changes constantly and our Privacy Notice and the Conditions of Use will change also. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and conditions, unless you have instructed us not to, but you should check our website frequently to see recent changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Notice applies to all information that we have about you and your account. We stand behind the promises we make, however, and will never materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information collected in the past without the consent of affected customers.

Should you wish to stop receiving any of out emails you can find an unsubscribe link at the footer of all out emails.

Company address - MenuPages, Unit 12 The Courtyard, Carmanhall Road, Sandyford, Dublin 18, Ireland   
Company email -  [info@menupages.ie](mailto:info@menupages.ie)  
Tele.NO - 353 (1) 2405555
